Neal Zheng

510-996-8933 nealzheng1@gmail.com zyx88615.github.io/Portfolio Fremont, CA 94538

SUMMARY

Multidisciplinary, driven Data Analyst with a passion for condensing large data into a simple to understand story. Adept at working independently and collaborating with teams across multiple functions. Experience to distill information from a wide variety of sources and effectively break down concepts in layman's terms for diverse audiences.

EDUCATION

University of California, Berkeley

Berkeley, California

Data Analytics Boot Camp

Feb, 2019 - September 2019

Coursework: Python for Finance, SQL Database, Data Mining, Machine Learning

Rutgers University, New Jersey Master of Quantitative Finance

Newark, New Jersey August 2015 – May 2017

Coursework: Econometrics, Fixed Income Analysis, Stochastic Calculus, Options

University of California, Davis Bachelor of Arts, Economics

Davis, California

September 2006 – June 2011

Coursework: Analysis of Variance, Regression Analysis, Linear Algebra, Differential Equations

PROJECTS

ETL Project May 2019

Extracted fundamental stock data from various sources

- Collected the missing information using python web-scraping & API calls
- Cleansed the data by adding and removing the raw attributes
- Designed and created relational database using MySQL

Machine Learning Project

Aug 2019

- Predicted box-office success of a movie based on YouTube data on Theatrical Trailer
- Transformed raw data into MySQL to prepare unruly data for machine learning
- Developed machine learning models such as using deep learning methods for classification and regression
- Built Web App and Dashboard for user searchable models to generate predictability/trends using python Flask
- Achieved 80% accuracy for movie success prediction

EXPERIENCE

Data Analytics Boot Camp, UC Berkeley, Berkeley, CA

Feb 2019 - Sept 2019

- Performed analysis on large data set and generate key statistic from the data
- Developed proficiency in core Python, SQL, APIs and relational database fundamentals
- Organized data into well-structured and easily retrievable data formats using MySQL and MongoDB
- Applied visualization and design principles with Tableau to create meaningful data visualizations

Experiential Learning, Rutgers/Citibank, Newark NJ, New York, NY

June 2016 - August 2016

- Worked in a research team that focused topics on the challenges of fixed income instrument pricing
- Researched and learned major regulations stemming from the Subprime Financial Crisis (TRACE, CCAR, PPNR etc.),
 and methodologies used by banks and third-party vendors for pricing Mortgage-Backed Security data
- Applied Monte Carlo methods to simulate the interest rate term structures

Licensed Premier Banker, Wells Fargo Advisor LLC, Union City, CA

Nov 2011 - August 2015

- Worked with Advisor to customize diversified financial plans for customers according to their financial goals
- Analyzed and presented different investment vehicles to help customers to make strategic investment decisions

SKILLS

IT: Python (Pandas, SciPy, Sklearn, Flask, PySpark, TensorFlow), C++, SQL/NoSQL (MySQL, MongoDB), Data Mining, Data Analysis, Data Visualization, JavaScript, API Interactions, Machine Learning, Neural Networks, VBA, Tableau